[upbeat music playing]
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
[airplane engine rumbling]
[indistinct chatter]
["Danger Zone" playing]
♪ Revvin' up your engine
Listen to her howlin' roar ♪
♪ Metal under tension
Beggin' you to touch and go ♪
♪ Highway to the danger zone ♪
♪ Ride into the danger zone ♪
♪ Headin' into twilight
Spreadin' out her wings tonight ♪
♪ She got you jumpin' off the deck
Shovin' into overdrive ♪
♪ Highway to the Danger Zone ♪
♪ I'll take you
Right into the Danger Zone ♪
[upbeat music concludes]
[soft music playing]
[man over PA] We're looking
at some of the hottest weather
we've had in almost a year...
[grunts]
[dramatic music playing]
[bike engine starts]
[bike engine rumbling]
[dramatic music concludes]
[Maverick] Hey.
What is it?
What?
We've been ordered to stand down.
They're scrapping the program.
They say we fell short.
The contract threshold is Mach 10.
Mach 10 is supposed to be in two months.
- Today's test point is Mach 9.
- Well. that's not good enough.
- Says who?
- Admiral Cain.
[Hondo] The Drone Ranger.
He wants our budget
for his unmanned program.
He's on his way to kill the test
and shut us down personally.
[airplane engine rumbling in distance]
[chuckles]
[exciting music playing]
Well. he isn't here yet.
They want Mach 10. Let's give 'em Mach 10.
[breathes heavily]
[inhales sharply]
Now. remember.
the contract threshold is Mach 10.
Not 10.1. Not 10.2. Mach 10.
That should keep the program alive.
I don't like that look. Mav.
It's the only one I got.
Control. this is Darkstar.
How do you read?
Darkstar. Control.
Loud and clear. How me?
[Maverick] Loud and clear.
Takeoff prechecks complete.
Ready for APU start.
[machine beeps]
- [Hondo] Ready. left engine start.
- [engine starts. rumbles]
[Hondo] Ready. right engine start.
Thumbs for taxi.
We are ready for taxi.
[plane engine rumbling]
[Maverick] Tower. this is Darkstar.
We are taxiing with information Alpha.
[operator] Darkstar.
you are clear to taxi.
Runway two-one. Winds two-one. zero-ten.
- Okay. Fuel temps are looking good.
- [Hondo] Control concurs.
[Maverick] Battery's holding at 95%.
Cabin pressure looks good.
[Hondo] Control concurs.
[Maverick] Tower. this is Darkstar.
We're ready for takeoff.
Requesting an unrestricted climb
to six-zero-zero and above.
[operator] Darkstar.
the runway and skies are yours.
[engineer] Rear Admiral Chester Cain.
[Hondo] Maverick.
Cain just pulled up to the gate.
It's not too late to stop. buddy.
You know what happens to you
if you go through with this.
[exciting music continues]
I know what happens to everyone else
if I don't.
Darkstar is ready for takeoff.
Everyone. go for takeoff.
starting with engine.
- Engine. go.
- Thermals. go.
- Fuel. go.
- Electric. go.
Control surfaces. go.
[Hondo] Darkstar. Control.
You're cleared for takeoff.
All right. sweetheart. One last ride.
[plane engine starts. rumbles]
[Hondo] Darkstar. you are cleared
above six-zero-zero. Increase to Mach 3.5.
[Maverick] Cleared above six-zero-zero.
Increased to Mach 3.5.
- [exciting music concludes]
- [door thudding]
- [tense music playing]
- Admiral. uh. just in time. sir.
I'm early. so are you.
You care to explain?
Transitioning to scramjet.
[engine whirring]
- [machine whirring]
- [tense music concludes]
[Hondo] Uh. Mav. Admiral Cain is asking...
- Ordering.
- Ordering that we bring her down.
[Maverick] Ah...
Alpha. three. oh...
assing... ach... ive point four. and...
Heading posi... Six.
This is where we've had trouble
with comms. sir.
It's the Earth's curvature.
It's called "Earth Bulge."
Did anyone offer you a coffee?
Okay.
[beeps]
[soft music playing]
[engineer] He's at Mach 7. pushing 8.
- [Hondo] Flight data?
- Receiving. Data is good.
[air whooshing]
Temperature's climbing.
Response is still stable.
We're feeling good.
[beeps]
[engineer] Mach 8.8.
Eight-point-nine. Mach 9.
He's the fastest man alive.
[plane engine rumbling]
Talk to me. Goose.
[engineer] Mach 9.1. 9.2.
Mach 9.3.
Nine-four.
Approaching high hypersonic.
[soft music concludes]
[plane engine rumbling]
[beeps]
Windshield hot caution.
- [device buzzing]
- Surface temp rising.
Come on. sweetheart.
just a little more. Just a little...
Come on!
[plane engine rumbling]
[beeps]
- [engineer] Mach 10!
- [all cheering]
Put that in your Pentagon budget!
Sir.
[breathes heavily]
Oh. don't do it. Don't do it.
Just...
a little push.
[beeps]
[softly] Holy shit.
[device buzzing]
[plane engine rumbling]
You got some balls. stick jockey.
I'll give you that.
[beeps]
Oh. shit.
[electricity crackles]
Maverick.
Maverick!
[explosion]
[horns honking]
- [bell chimes]
- [indistinct chatter]
[soft music playing]
[gulps]
[Maverick] Thank you.
Where am I?
Earth.
- [helicopter whirring]
- [soft music concludes]
[Admiral Cain] Maverick.
Thirty-plus years of service.
Combat medals.
Citations.
Only man to shoot down
three enemy planes in the last 40 years.
"Distinguished."
Yet. you can't get a promotion.
you won't retire.
And despite your best efforts.
you refuse to die.
You should be at least
a two-star admiral by now.
if not a senator.
Yet here you are.
Captain.
Why is that?
It's one of life's mysteries. sir.
This isn't a joke. I asked you a question.
I'm where I belong. sir.
Well. the navy doesn't see it that way.
Not anymore.
[plane engine rumbling in distance]
These planes you've been testing. Captain.
One day. sooner than later.
they won't need pilots at all.
Pilots that need to sleep.
eat. take a piss.
Pilots that disobey orders.
All you did was buy some time
for those men out there.
The future is coming.
And you're not in it.
Escort this man off the base.
Take him to his quarters.
Wait with him while he packs his gear.
I want him on the road
to North Island within the hour.
North Island. sir?
Call came in with impeccable timing.
right as I was driving here
to ground your ass once and for all.
It... It galls me to say it. but...
for reasons known only to the Almighty
and your guardian angel...
you've been called back to TOPGUN.
[tense music playing]
- Sir?
- You are dismissed. Captain.
The end is inevitable. Maverick.
Your kind is headed for extinction.
Maybe so. sir. [inhales]
But not today.
[plane engine rumbling]
[bike engine rumbling]
[cheerful music concludes]
[Cyclone]
Captain Pete Maverick Mitchell.
Your reputation precedes you.
Thank you. sir.
Wasn't a compliment.
I'm Admiral Beau Simpson.
I'm the air boss.
- I believe you know Admiral Bates.
- Warlock. sir.
Must admit.
I wasn't expecting an invitation back.
They're called orders. Maverick.
You two have something in common.
Cyclone here was first in his class
back in '88.
Actually. sir. I finished second.
Just want to manage expectations.
[sighs]
The target...
is an unsanctioned
uranium enrichment plant
built in violation
of a multilateral NATO treaty.
The uranium produced there
represents a direct threat
to our allies in the region.
The Pentagon has tasked us with assembling
a strike team and taking it out
before it becomes fully operational.
The plant sits in an underground bunker
at the end of this valley.
Said valley is GPS-jammed
and defended by an extensive
surface-to-air missile array.
serving a limited number
of fifth-generation fighters.
which in turn are backed up
by a plentiful reserve
of surplus aircraft.
Even a few old F-14s.
Seems like we're not the only ones
holding on to old relics.
[Warlock] What's your read. Captain?
Well. sir. normally.
this would be a cakewalk
for the F-35 stealth.
but the GPS-jamming negates that.
And a surface-to-air threat necessitates
a low-level laser-guided strike
tailor-made for the F-18. I figure.
Two precision bombs. minimum.
Makes it four aircraft flying in pairs.
That is one hell of a steep climb
out of there.
exposing you to all
the surface-to-air missiles.
You survive that...
it's a dogfight all the way home.
All requirements for which you have
real-world experience.
Not in the same mission. sir.
No.
No. someone's not coming back from this.
Can it be done or not?
How soon before the plant
becomes operational?
Three weeks. maybe less.
Well. it's been a while
since I've flown an F-18 and...
I'm not sure who I'd trust to fly
the other three.
- But I'll find a way to make it work.
- I think you misunderstand. Captain.
Sir?
We don't want you to fly it.
We want you to teach it.
Teach. sir?
We've recalled 12 TOPGUN graduates
from their squadrons.
We want you to narrow that pool
down to six.
They'll fly the mission.
Is there a problem. Captain?
You know there is. sir.
Yeah.
[Warlock] Bradley Bradshaw.
a.k.a. Rooster.
I understand you used to fly
with his old man.
What was his call sign?
Goose. sir.
Tragic what happened.
Captain Mitchell was cleared
of any wrongdoing.
Goose's death was an accident.
[Cyclone] Is that how you see it. Captain?
Is that how Goose's son sees it?
With all due respect. sir.
I'm not a teacher.
You were a TOPGUN instructor before.
That was almost 30 years ago.
I lasted two months.
- It's not where I belong.
- Then let me be perfectly blunt.
You were not my first choice.
In fact. you weren't even on the list.
You are here at the request
of Admiral Kazansky.
Now. Iceman happens to be a man
I deeply admire.
and he seems to think
that you have something
left to offer the navy.
What that is. I can't imagine.
You don't have to take this job.
But let me be clear.
This will be your last post. Captain.
You fly for TOPGUN.
or you don't fly for the navy ever again.
[tense music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[Coyote] Twenty bucks. you can't get
three in a row.
[cell phone vibrating]
[Penny] Oh. you've got to be kidding me.
[tense music concludes]
Pete.
[upbeat music playing in background]
- Penny?
- [chuckles]
- [Maverick] What are you doing here?
- I should ask you the same thing.
- Well. that is a long story.
- [Penny] I doubt that.
- Yeah.
- Who'd you piss off this time?
- Another admiral.
- Exactly.
- Are you mad at me?
- [Penny] Oh. Pete.
I can never stay mad at you.
That's the problem.
[scoffs]
I got to say.
North Island is the one place
I thought for sure I'd never run into you.
[Maverick] Hmm.
- How long you been here?
- Bought this place about three years ago.
- Three years?
- [Penny] Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Not long after you got shipped off
to the desert
for pissing off that other admiral.
That was three years ago?
You must be in a lot of trouble.
No way you'd come back here willingly.
Well... you'll sort it out.
No. I think. uh...
- I think this is it.
- [Penny] Come on. Pete.
You've been saying
that as long as I've known you.
You said it after they busted you
for taking me on a joyride in that F-18.
- Hmm.
- [Penny] Then the next thing I know.
you're off to Bosnia.
Then Iraq. both times.
You get yourself in trouble...
Iceman makes a call.
and you're back in the air.
- Penny. this is different.
- [Penny] Pete. trust me.
As improbable as it seems right now.
somehow. you'll be back in a fighter plane
with your tail on fire.
- Penny...
- [Penny] Too late.
What?
You were about to ask me
what time I get off.
Don't give me that look.
I'm not giving you any look. I swear.
It always ends the same with us. Pete.
Let's not start this time.
- Okay.
You look good.
[bell ringing]
[crowd cheers]
Much appreciated. pal.
What am I missing?
"Disrespect a lady. the navy.
or put your cell phone on my bar..."
"...and you buy a round."
For everyone?
I'm afraid rules are rules.
You're lucky it's early.
- [Coyote] Oh. come on!
- What do we have here?
If it ain't Phoenix!
And here I thought
we were special. Coyote.
Turns out the invite went to anyone.
Fellas. this here's Bagman.
- Hangman.
- Whatever.
You're looking at the only naval aviator
on active duty
- with a confirmed air-to-air kill.
- Stop.
Mind you. the other guy
was in a museum piece
from the Korean War.
- Cold War.
- Different wars. same century.
Not this one.
Who are your friends?
- Payback.
- Fanboy.
- Hey. Coyote.
- Hey.
- Who's he?
- Who's who?
- When did you get in?
- Oh. I've... I've been here the whole time.
- The man's a stealth pilot.
- Literally.
Weapons systems officer. actually.
With no sense of humor.
What do they call you?
- Bob.
- No. your call sign.
Uh...
- Bob.
- [Phoenix] Bob Floyd.
You're my new backseater? From Lemoore?
Looks like it. yeah.
Nine-ball. Bob.
Rack 'em.
Okay. [chuckles]
- [Hangman] Penny. my dear.
- [Penny] Yeah.
I'll have four more on the old-timer.
- [car engine rumbling]
- ["Tramp" playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[Phoenix] Bradshaw!
Is that you?
This is how I find out you're stateside?
- Yeah. I just thought I'd surprise you.
- [Phoenix] Hmm.
[groans]
I guess I surprised you back.
- It's good to see you.
- Good to see you too.
- Here you go.
- [Hangman] Thank you.
Much appreciated. Pops.
How about ringing me up
before the evening rush?
Bradshaw. As I live and breathe.
Hangman. you look good.
Well. I am good. Rooster.
I'm very good.
In fact. I am too good to be true.
So...
anybody know what this special detachment
is all about?
No. mission's a mission.
They don't confront me.
What I wanna know.
who's gonna be team leader?
And which one of y'all has
what it takes to follow me?
Hangman. the only place you'll lead anyone
is an early grave.
Whoo!
Well. anyone who follows you
is just gonna run out of fuel.
But that's just you. ain't it. Rooster?
You're snug on that perch.
waiting for just the right moment...
that never comes.
I love this song!
♪ Slow ride ♪
♪ Take it easy... ♪
Well. he hasn't changed.
Nope. Sure hasn't.
♪ Take it easy... ♪
[Hangman] Check it out.
More patches.
[Coyote] That's Harvard. Yale. Omaha.
Shit. that's Fritz.
What the hell kind of mission is this?
That's not the question
we should be asking.
Everyone here is the best there is.
Who the hell are they gonna get
to teach us?
- It's been declined.
- You're kidding.
- [music stops]
- [crowd clamoring]
[indistinct chatter]
[piano playing]
[Phoenix] Hey. guys. come on.
[Maverick] How about...
That won't cover it.
Uh. I'll come by tomorrow
and bring you the cash.
I'm afraid.
Rules are rules. Pete.
[bell ringing]
[crowd cheers]
[man] Overboard!
- [crowd] Overboard! Overboard!
- Really?
[crowd] Overboard! Overboard! Overboard!
Overboard! Overboard!
[crowd applauds. cheers]
- Great to see you. Pete!
- [crowd] Overboard!
Overboard! Overboard!
- Overboard!
- [crowd cheering]
Thanks for the beers!
Come back anytime!
[exhales sharply]
[crowd shouting] Loser! Loser!
Loser! Loser!
♪ You shake my nerves
And you rattle my brain ♪
♪ Too much love drives a man insane
You broke my will. but what a thrill ♪
♪ Goodness gracious
Great balls of fire! ♪
♪ I laughed at love
'Cause I thought it was funny ♪
♪ But you came along
And you moved me. honey ♪
♪ I changed my mind. this love is fine
Goodness gracious. great balls of fire! ♪
♪ Kiss me. baby... ♪
[somber music playing]
♪ Goodness gracious
great balls of fire! ♪
[Maverick] Altitude 8.000.
Seven thousand.
Goose.
I can't reach the ejection handle.
Eject. eject. eject!
[explosion]
[somber music continues]
[Maverick] Goose! Oh. no!
God. he loved flying with you. Maverick.
♪ That you're mine. mine. mine. mine... ♪
[somber music continues]
♪ Come on. baby. you're driving me crazy
Goodness gracious. great balls of fire! ♪
[somber music concludes]
[woman] Attention on deck!
[plane engine rumbling]
[Warlock] Morning.
Welcome to your special training
detachment. Be seated.
I'm Admiral Bates. NAWDC commander.
You're all TOPGUN graduates.
The elite.
The best of the best.
That was yesterday.
The enemy's new fifth-generation fighter
has leveled the playing field.
Details are few. but you can be sure
we no longer possess
the technological advantage.
Success. now more than ever.
comes down to the man
or woman in the box.
Half of you will make the cut.
One of you will be named mission leader.
The other half will remain in reserve.
Your instructor is a TOPGUN graduate
with real-world experience
in every mission aspect
you will be expected to master.
His exploits are legendary.
And he's considered
to be one of the finest pilots
this program has ever produced.
What he has to teach you
may very well mean the difference
between life and death.
I give you Captain Pete Mitchell.
Call sign "Maverick."
Good morning.
The F-18 NATOPS.
It contains everything
they want you to know about your aircraft.
I'm assuming you know the book
inside and out.
- Damn right.
- Yeah!
- Damn straight.
- You got it.
[plane engine rumbling in the background]
So does your enemy.
And we're off.
But what the enemy doesn't know
is your limits.
I intend to find them...
test them. push beyond.
Today. we'll start
with what you only think you know.
You show me what you're made of.
[plane engine rumbling]
[Maverick] Rooster.
Bradley.
Lieutenant Bradshaw!
[Rooster] Yes. sir.
Let's not do it like this.
You gonna wash me out?
That'll be up to you. not me.
Am I dismissed?
- [plane engine rumbling]
- ["Won't Get Fooled Again" playing]
Good morning. aviators.
This is your captain speaking.
Welcome to basic fighter maneuvers.
As briefed. today's exercise
is dogfighting.
Guns only. no missiles.
We do not go below the hard deck
of 5.000 feet.
Working as a team.
you have to shoot me down. or else.
- Or else what. sir?
- Or else. I shoot back.
If I shoot either one of you down.
you both lose.
- This guy needs an ego check.
- We'll see to that.
What say we put some skin in the game?
What do you have in mind?
Whoever gets shot down first
has to do 200 push-ups.
[Maverick] Guys. that's a lot of push-ups.
Well. they don't call it
an exercise for nothing. sir.
[Maverick] You got yourself a deal.
gentlemen.
Fight's on. let's turn and burn.
[plane engines rumbling]
[Rooster] Fanboy. you see him?
[Fanboy] Nothing on the radar up ahead.
He must be somewhere behind us.
- [Fanboy] Damn it!
- What the hell?
[Fanboy] Oh. shit!
♪ We don't get fooled again ♪
[Maverick] Easy. Maverick. Let's try
not to get fired on the first day.
[Fanboy] Tally. tally. tally!
Maverick's coming in!
- Break left!
- [Payback] Breaking left.
[Maverick] Payback. where's your wingman?
- [Payback] Rooster. where are you?
- [Rooster] I got your back.
I'm coming. hang in there. hang in there.
[Payback] Hurry up. man! Hurry up!
- [Rooster] Payback. break right.
- [Payback] Breaking right.
[Maverick] Rooster just saved your life.
fellas. But it's gonna cost him.
[Rooster] Not this time. old man.
[Maverick] Don't let him
get to you. Maverick.
[Payback] Rooster. you're too low!
Pull up! You're hitting the hard deck!
- [automated voice] Altitude. Altitude.
- [Rooster] Oh. shit.
- [Maverick] That's a kill.
- Down! 109.
- Down! 110.
- [breathes shakily]
- That should be us down there.
- [Hondo] One-eleven.
- But it's not.
- [Hondo] Down!
And now you know
a little something about Rooster.
[Hangman] Whoo!
Hey. hold that tarmac down
till we get back. brother.
Get in here. good boys.
[laughs]
- [Maverick] That's a kill.
- [Fanboy] Damn!
- [Maverick] Smoked.
- [Harvard] Damn it.
[Yale grunts]
It was all fun and games
in that selfie. wasn't it? Down!
[Hangman] Say. Phoenix.
And how's about we tell everybody
"Bob" stands for something?
[Coyote] Other than Robert.
- I'm in.
- [Phoenix] Don't take the bait. Bob.
Want to know why we call him Hangman?
Oh. wait. I got it. "Baby On Board."
[laughs]
- [plane engine rumbling]
- Shit!
[Maverick] Greetings. aviators.
Fight's on.
[Hangman] All right. Phoenix.
let's take this guy out!
Watch your back. Phoenix.
- [Hangman] Break right!
- [Phoenix] Breaking right.
[Bob] Where's he going?
[Phoenix] That's why we call him Hangman.
He'll always hang you out to dry.
[Maverick] Leaving your wingman.
There's a strategy
I haven't seen in a while.
[Hangman] He called you a man. Phoenix.
You gonna take that?
[Phoenix] So long as he doesn't call
you a man.
Talk to me. Bob. where's Maverick?
[Bob] Jesus.
his nose is already coming around!
[Phoenix] Get him off me. Hangman!
[Hangman] For all you folks at home.
this is how you bury a fossil.
[Maverick] All right. Hangman.
Time to teach you a lesson.
- You're out. Phoenix.
- [Phoenix] Son of a bitch!
- [machine beeping]
- [grunts]
[Maverick] That's it.
[Hangman] Let's go. Mav.
Let's see what you got.
[Maverick] Come get me.
[Hangman] Evil be gone. Hangman's coming.
[Maverick] Yeah. you're good.
I'll give you that.
[plane engines rumbling]
[Hangman] Shit.
Phoenix. I can't see him. How close am I?
- Phoenix?
- I'm dead. dickhead.
- See you in the afterlife. Bagman.
- [scoffs]
- [Hangman] Where is he? Where is he?
- [Maverick] That's a kill.
Seventy-nine. down. Eighty. down.
[Maverick] Let's go. who's next?
- I got you. Omaha.
- [Omaha] Damn it!
- [Maverick] Lights out. Coyote.
- Copy kill.
[Hondo] Down. 51. Down. 52.
[upbeat music concludes]
[Hangman] So. Rooster. mind if I ask you
a personal question?
[Rooster] Would it matter if I did?
[Hangman] So. what's the story
with you and Maverick?
- It seems like he's got you rattled.
- [Rooster] That's none of your business.
- Now where the hell is he?
- [Maverick] Been here the whole time.
[Hangman] Holy shit.
[Maverick] You see me now?
Come on. let's get it over with.
[Rooster breathes heavily] Fight's on!
[Hangman] What is with these two?
[Maverick] All right. you put us here.
How you gonna get yourself out?
[Rooster] You can bail out anytime.
[Maverick] How low you wanna go. Rooster?
[Rooster] I can go as low as you. sir!
And that's saying something.
[Maverick] What's past is past.
For both of us.
[Rooster] You'd like to believe that.
wouldn't you?
[Hangman] Hard deck is 5.000 feet. fellas.
You are running out of room.
[Maverick] Your strategy
is about to run us into the ground.
- [Rooster] What's your move?
- [automated voice] Altitude. Altitude.
Altitude.
- Altitude. Altitude.
- [Rooster breathing heavily]
[automated voice] Altitude.
Altitude. Altitude.
- Pull up! Pull up! Pull up! Pull up!
- [Maverick grunts]
[automated voice] Pull up! Pull up!
[Hangman] You got it.
Don't think. just do.
Come on. Rooster. you got him!
Drop down and take the shot!
[Rooster] It's too low.
[Maverick] Too late. you had your chance.
That's a kill. knock it off.
[breathes heavily]
- [Rooster] Damn it! [breathes heavily]
- [Hangman] Same old Rooster.
[Maverick] Go see Hondo
about your push-ups.
All right. that's enough.
Rooster. that's enough. man.
[groans]
[Phoenix] Breaking the hard deck.
insubordination.
- Are you trying to get kicked out?
- Don't worry about it.
Look. I'm going on this mission.
But if you get kicked out.
you leave us flying with Hangman.
- Talk to me. What the hell was that?
- He pulled my papers.
- What? Who?
- [Rooster] Maverick.
He pulled my application
to the Naval Academy.
Set me back four years.
Why would he do that?
[Cyclone] The hard deck is 5.000 feet
above ground level.
A parameter is set
not just for the safety of our pilots.
but for the safety of their aircraft.
Five thousand feet is not just a rule.
It is a law. as immutable as gravity.
The hard deck will be much lower
for the mission. sir.
And it will not change
without my approval!
Especially not in the middle
of an exercise.
And that cobra maneuver of yours?
That could've got all three of you killed.
I never want to see that shit again.
What exactly do you suppose
you were teaching. Captain?
That as good as they are. sir.
they still have something to learn.
You are talking about the best fighter
pilots on the planet. Captain.
And they've been told that
their entire career.
while they've been dropping bombs
from a high altitude
with little to no dogfighting.
The parameters of this mission
call for something
they have never encountered...
Okay. you have less than three weeks
to teach them how to fight as a team...
- and how to strike the target.
- And how to come home.
And how to come home. sir.
Every mission has its risks.
These pilots accept that.
I don't. sir.
Every morning. from this day forward.
you will brief us
on your instructional plans in writing.
And nothing will change
without my express approval.
- Including the hard deck. sir?
- Especially the hard deck. Captain.
- [Maverick] Sir.
- What is this?
It's a request
to lower the hard deck. sir.
To practice a low-level bombing run
per the mission parameters.
You could learn a thing or two
about timing. Captain.
[Hangman] Yo. Coyote.
Take a look at this.
[Coyote] The man. the legend. there he is.
No. no. no. Next to him.
He look familiar to you?
What have we here?
[Hangman] "Bradshaw."
As I live and breathe.
- [Maverick] Hey. Theo. you got big.
- [Amelia] Hey. Mav.
Amelia?
- I know. I got big.
- [chuckles] Yes.
Bar opens at 5:00.
- No. I just came by to pay off a debt.
- [Amelia] Mom!
- Hey. how's your dad?
- With his wife. in Hawaii.
Mom!
Mav says he owes you money.
- Oh. don't worry about it.
- I insist.
[sighs]
Thank you. Captain.
Consider your tab closed.
Captain? Still?
- A highly decorated captain.
- Finish up.
We have to get the boat to the yard.
- [Amelia] I can't go.
- What do you mean you can't go?
[Amelia] Test tomorrow. I have to study.
They only told us today.
Well. I can't sail her alone.
Just use the engine.
[Penny] Why are we taking her to the yard?
- To fix the engine.
- [Penny] To fix the engine. [chuckles]
I can help.
[waves crashing]
[Penny] Little rougher
than I was expecting.
[Maverick] You don't say.
Pull on the backstay. De-power the sail.
Okay.
What does that mean?
[waves crashing]
You're supposed to be in the navy!
I don't sail boats. Penny. I land on them.
It's sort of like raising
the flaps on an airplane.
- [Maverick] So how do I do that?
- You pull on that green line up there.
Green line.
[Penny] Yep. pull it hard.
Yep. crank that winch right there.
tighten the jib.
- Crank it. You okay?
- Yeah.
Good.
Now... you ready?
[soft music playing]
- [Maverick] For what?
- The afterburner.
[air whooshing]
Now you're in the navy.
[Penny] Thanks for helping out today.
I'm not exactly sure I helped.
Hmm.
Don't give me that look.
- What look?
- [Penny] That one.
Good night. Pete.
Night. Penny.
[exhales deeply]
[chuckles. sighs]
- [Amelia] Mom. is that you?
- [Penny] Yeah. it's me.
- I'll make you dinner.
- [Amelia] Okay.
[soft music concludes]
Time is your greatest enemy.
[suspenseful music playing]
Phase one of the mission
will be a low-level ingress
attacking in two-plane teams.
You'll fly along this narrow canyon
to your target.
Radar-guided surface-to-air missiles
defend the area.
These SAMs. they're lethal.
But they were designed to protect
the skies above.
not the canyon below.
That's because the enemy knows no one
is insane enough
to try and fly below them.
That's exactly what I'm gonna train you
to do.
On the day.
your altitude will be 100 feet maximum.
You exceed this altitude.
radar will spot you...
- [device beeps]
- [Maverick] ...and you're dead.
Your airspeed will be 660 knots.
Minimum.
Time to target. two and a half minutes.
That's because fifth-generation fighters
wait at an air base nearby.
In a head-to-head with these planes
in your F-18s. you're dead.
That's why you need to get in.
hit your target and be gone
before these planes
even have a chance of catching you.
This makes time your greatest adversary.
[plane engine rumbling]
[Maverick] You'll fly a route
in your nav system
that simulates the canyon.
The faster you navigate this canyon.
the harder it'll be to stay
under the radar of these enemy SAMs.
- [Phoenix grunts]
- [Maverick] The tighter the turns.
the more intensely the force
of gravity
- on your body multiplies...
- [Hangman grunts]
[Maverick] ...compressing your lungs.
forcing the blood from your brain.
Impairing your judgment and reaction time.
So for today's lesson.
we're gonna take it easy on you.
Max ceiling. 300 feet.
Time to target. three minutes.
Good luck.
- [plane engine rumbling]
- [suspenseful music continues]
[Bob] Time to target is one minute 30.
We are two seconds behind.
Increase to 480 knots.
[Phoenix] We got to move. Coyote.
[Coyote] Copy. increasing speed. [grunts]
[Phoenix] Shit!
[device beeps]
Why are they dead?
We broke the 300-foot ceiling.
and a SAM took us out.
No. why are they dead?
I slowed down and didn't give a warning.
it was my fault.
Was there a reason you didn't communicate
with your team?
- I was focusing on...
- One that their family will accept
at the funeral.
None. sir.
Why didn't you anticipate the turn?
You were briefed on the terrain.
Don't tell me. tell it to his family.
[suspenseful music continues]
[Payback] Hangman. ease up.
The canyon's getting tighter.
[Hangman] Negative. Payback.
Increase your speed.
[Payback] You're going too fast. man.
[Hangman] Well. no harm in being ahead
of schedule.
[Payback] Damn it. slow down!
I can't stay on the course!
[Fanboy] You're gonna hit the wall!
Watch out! Watch out! Watch out!
[plane engines rumbling]
- [device beeps]
- What happened?
[Hangman] Well. I flew as fast as I could.
Kind of like my ass depended on it.
And you put your team in danger
and your wingman's dead.
They couldn't keep up.
- [suspenseful music continues]
- [plane engines rumbling]
[Yale] Rooster.
we're 20 seconds behind and dropping.
[Rooster] We're fine. speed is good.
[Yale] Increase to 500 knots.
[Rooster] Negative. Yale. Hold your speed.
[Yale] Rooster. we're late!
[Rooster] We're alive.
We'll make up time in the straightaway.
[Yale] We are not gonna make it.
[Rooster] Just trust me.
Maintain your speed. we can make it.
- Why are you dead?
- [suspenseful music concludes]
[Maverick] You're team leader up there.
Why are you. why is your team. dead?
Sir. he's the only one
who made it to the target.
A minute late.
He gave enemy aircraft time
to shoot him down.
- He is dead.
- You don't know that.
You're not flying fast enough.
You don't have a second to waste.
We made it to the target.
And superior enemy aircraft
intercepted you on your way out.
- Then it's a dogfight.
- Against fifth-generation fighters.
- [Rooster] Yeah. we'd still have a chance.
- [Maverick] In an F-18.
It's not the plane. sir. it's the pilot.
Exactly!
There's more than one way to fly
this mission.
[Hangman] You really don't get it. [sighs]
On this mission.
a man flies like Maverick here.
or a man does not come back.
No offense intended.
Yet somehow you always manage.
Look. I don't mean to criticize.
You're conservative. that's all.
- Lieutenant.
- [Hangman] We're going into combat. son.
on a level no living pilot's ever seen.
Not even him.
That's no time
to be thinking about the past.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Rooster.
I can't be the only one that knows
- that Maverick flew with his old man.
- That's enough.
Or that Maverick was flying.
when his old man...
- Lieutenant. that's enough!
- [Phoenix] Hey! Hey!
- That's enough.
- You son of a bitch!
[Payback] Hey. come on!
I'm cool. I'm cool. Hey. hey. hey. hey.
[Maverick] That's enough.
[Hangman] He's not cut out
for this mission.
- That's enough!
- You know it.
[breathes heavily]
You know I'm right.
You're all dismissed.
[somber music playing]
[cell phone vibrating]
[bike engine rumbling]
[Sarah chuckles]
Maverick...
It's come back?
No one knows.
There's nothing else they can do.
Even speaking is painful now.
Sarah. I'm so sorry.
[Iceman coughing]
[coughs]
- [somber music concludes]
- [sighs]
Admiral.
How's my wingman?
[keyboard keys clacking]
Please. don't worry about me.
What can I do for you?
[exhales deeply]
All right.
[chuckles softly]
Well. Rooster's still angry with me
about what I did.
I thought eventually
he would understand why.
I hoped he'd forgive me.
[keyboard keys clacking]
The mission is less than three weeks away.
The kid's not ready.
[keyboard keys clacking]
He doesn't want what I have to give.
Ice. please. don't ask me to send
someone else to die.
Please don't... [inhales deeply]
...don't ask me to send him.
Send me.
[keyboard keys clacking]
[sniffs]
[breathes sharply]
[somber music playing]
I don't know how.
[exhales sharply]
I'm not a teacher. Ice.
I'm a fighter pilot.
A naval aviator.
[inhales deeply]
It's not what I am.
It's who I am.
How do I teach that?
Even if I could teach it.
it's not what Rooster wants.
It's not what the navy wants.
That's why they canned me the last time.
The only reason I'm here is you.
If I send him on this mission...
he might never come home.
And if I don't send him.
he'll never forgive me.
Either way. I could lose him forever.
[exhales deeply]
I know. I know.
[breathes deeply]
- [somber music continues]
- [Iceman groans]
[Iceman coughing]
The navy needs Maverick.
The kid needs Maverick.
That's why I fought for you.
That's why you're still here.
[Maverick] Thank you. Ice. for everything.
One last thing. who's the better pilot?
You or me?
This is a nice moment. let's not ruin it.
[Iceman laughs]
[somber music concludes]
["I Ain't Worried" playing]
♪ I don't know what you've been told ♪
♪ But time is running out
No need to take it slow... ♪
Let's go!
♪ I'm steppin' to you. toe-to-toe
I should be scared ♪
- ♪ Honey. maybe so... ♪
- All right.
♪ But I ain't worried 'bout it right now ♪
♪ Keepin' dreams alive. 1999 heroes
I ain't worried 'bout it right now ♪
♪ Swimmin' in the floods... ♪
- Touchdown!
- ♪ Dancing on the clouds below ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it... ♪
[crowd cheering]
[whistle blows]
[Rooster] Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Yeah!
- ♪ I don't know what you've been told ♪
- Whoo!
Whoo!
♪ But time is running out
So spend it like it's gold ♪
♪ I'm livin' like I'm nine zeros
Got no regrets even when I'm broke ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it right now
Keepin' dreams alive. 1999 heroes ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it right now ♪
♪ Swimming in the floods
Dancing on the clouds below ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it... ♪
- [crowd cheering]
- [whistle blowing]
[indistinct chatter]
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it... ♪
- Hey! Rooster!
- ♪ I ain't worried 'bout it... ♪
[crowd cheering. laughing]
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it... ♪
- [Maverick] Sir?
- What is this?
This is dogfight football.
Offense and defense at the same time.
[Cyclone] Who's winning?
I think they stopped
keeping score a while ago.
This detachment still has some training
to complete. Captain.
- Every available minute matters.
- Yes. sir.
So why are we out here playing games?
You said to create a team. sir.
There's your team.
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it... ♪
[crowd cheers]
[all] Bob! Bob! Bob! Bob! Bob!
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it right now ♪
♪ Keepin' dreams alive. 1999 heroes ♪
♪ Swimming in the floods
Dancing on the clouds below ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
["I Ain't Worried" concludes]
[soft music playing]
Should I go? Before Amelia gets back?
- She'll be at her friend's house tonight.
- Good.
You and Amelia. you seem...
[inhales deeply]
...a lot closer than when I last saw you.
- Yeah. Yeah. we are.
- How do you manage?
[inhales deeply]
Well...
you know. she always wanted more freedom
than I thought she was ready for.
[Maverick] Hmm.
Where'd she get that from.
- I wonder?
- [chuckles]
I guess I realized
I also had to trust her.
Let her make
some of her own mistakes sometimes.
- Not an easy choice.
- [Penny] Hmm.
Is that what happened with Rooster?
I pulled his papers
from the Naval Academy.
Took years off his career.
Why?
His mother never wanted him to fly.
not after what happened to Goose.
She made me promise before she died. so...
Does Rooster know that?
He will always resent me for what I did.
Why should he resent her too?
- Not an easy choice.
- [Maverick] Hmm.
I was trying to be the father he lost.
I just...
I wish I would've done it better.
But... the truth is...
I didn't think he was ready.
Is he ready now?
- [door closing]
- [Amelia] Mom. I'm home!
I thought you were staying
at Karen's tonight.
[Amelia] Karen's sick.
And I've got homework to do.
- I should go.
- You should go. [sighs]
- Have you had dinner yet?
- [Amelia] Not yet. you wanna go out?
No. it's okay. I'll make you something.
I'll be down in a sec!
- Wait! Not that way.
- What?
Look... Look. I have an example to set.
I can't be bringing guys home
on a first date.
This is not our first date.
You know what I mean.
[exhales deeply]
Okay.
Fine.
But this is the last time
I go out your window.
- We'll see.
- No. No. I mean it.
I'm never gonna leave you again.
Oh. shut up. [smooches]
Go on. get out of here.
[grunts]
Just don't break her heart again.
[sighs]
[Warlock] Good morning.
The uranium enrichment plant
that is your target
will be operational earlier than expected.
Raw uranium will be delivered
to the plant in ten days' time.
As a result. your mission
has been moved up one week.
in order to avoid contaminating
the target valley with radiation.
Sir. no one here has successfully flown
a low-level course.
Nevertheless. you've been ordered
to move on.
- Captain.
- [intense music playing]
[Maverick] We have one week left
to focus on phase two.
It's the most difficult stage
of the mission.
It's a pop-up strike with a steep dive.
requiring nothing less
than two consecutive miracles.
Two pairs of F-18s will fly
in a welded-wing formation.
Teamwork. Precise coordination
of these aircraft is essential
to both the mission's success
and your survival.
As you know. the plant rests
between two mountains.
On final approach.
you'll invert directly into a steep dive.
This allows you to maintain
the lowest possible altitude.
And the only possible attack angle.
Your target is an impact point
less than three meters wide.
The two-seat aircraft will paint
the target with a laser bullseye.
[beeps]
[Maverick] The first pair
will breach the reactor
by dropping a laser-guided bomb
on an exposed ventilation hatch.
[device beeps]
[Maverick] This will create an opening
for the second pair.
That's miracle number one.
The second team
will deliver the kill shot...
and destroy the target.
[device beeps]
That's miracle number two.
If either team misses the target...
[explosions]
- [Hangman] That's a miss.
- [Maverick] ...the mission is a failure.
[Rooster] Damn it!
[Maverick] Egress is a steep high-G
climb out to avoid hitting this mountain.
[plane engine rumbling]
A steep climb at that speed.
you're pulling at least eight G's.
Nine. minimum.
The stress limit of the F-18's airframe
is seven point five.
[Maverick] That's the accepted limit.
To survive this mission.
you'll pull beyond that.
even if it means bending your airframe.
[plane engine rumbling]
[Maverick] You'll be pulling so hard.
you'll weigh close to 2.000 pounds.
- your skull crushing your spine...
- [Phoenix] Fuck.
[Maverick] ...your lungs imploding
like an elephant's sitting on your chest.
fighting with everything you have
just to keep from blacking out.
[Rooster groans. pants]
And this is where you'll be
at your most vulnerable.
This is Coffin Corner.
Assuming you avoid crashing
into this mountain.
you'll climb straight up into enemy radar
while losing all of your airspeed.
Within seconds. you'll be fired upon
by enemy SAMs.
You've all faced
sustained G's before. but this.
this is gonna take you
and your aircraft to the breaking point.
Sir. is this even achievable?
The answer to that question
will come down to the pilot in the box.
- [intense music concludes]
- [plane engine rumbling]
- [Phoenix] Talk to me. Bob.
- [Bob] We are 12 seconds late on target.
- We gotta move! We gotta move!
- [Phoenix] Shit.
[Coyote] Copy. try to stay with me.
[beeps]
[Coyote gasps] Wait. who's that?
[Maverick] Blue Team.
you've been spotted.
- [Coyote] Shit. it's Maverick.
- [Phoenix] What the hell is he doing here?
[Maverick] I'm a bandit on course
to intercept.
Blue Team. what are you gonna do?
[Bob] He's 20 miles left. Ten o'clock.
Seven hundred knots closure.
[Coyote] Your call.
What do you want to do?
[Phoenix] Continue. we're close.
Stay on target.
- [Bob] He's swinging around to the north!
- [Coyote] Stand by for pop-up.
- [Phoenix] Be ready on that laser. Bob.
- [Bob] Copy. I'm on it.
[Maverick] Blue Team.
bandit is still closing.
[Coyote] Popping now. [groans]
[plane engine rumbling]
[Phoenix groans]
[Coyote] Talk to me. Bob.
Where's Maverick?
[Bob] He's five miles out.
he's coming fast.
- [Phoenix] Target's in sight.
- [Coyote] Where's my laser. Bob?
[Bob] Deadeye! Deadeye! It's no good.
Sorry. I can't get a lock.
[Coyote] We're out of time.
I'm dropping blind.
- [explosion]
- [Coyote] Damn it. missed!
[Phoenix groans]
[Coyote grunts]
- [beeps]
- [Maverick] That's tone.
[Coyote] Maverick's got missile lock
on us.
[Phoenix] Shit! We're dead.
[Maverick] Blue Team. that's a fail.
Level out. Coyote.
Coyote? Do you copy?
Coyote. come in.
Coyote. level wings.
Oh. my God. he's in G-LOC.
Coyote? Coyote?
- [Phoenix] He's gonna burn in!
- [Maverick] I'm going after him.
[plane engine rumbling]
[Maverick] Come on. Give me tone.
give me tone. give me tone!
- [beeps]
- [Maverick] Snap out of it. Coyote.
Come on! Come on!
Come on. Coyote. Come on. come on!
- God damn it! Coyote!
- [Phoenix] Pull up!
- [Maverick] Coyote! Coyote!
[Maverick] Coyote. you okay? You okay?
[Coyote] Yeah. I'm okay. I'm good. [pants]
[Maverick] Good. Good.
That's enough for today.
[Phoenix] That was close.
[Maverick] Too close.
- Bird strike! Bird strike!
- [Phoenix] Bird strike!
[device beeps]
- [Bob] Phoenix. left engine's on fire!
- [Phoenix] Climbing.
Throttling back. Shutting off fuel
to left engine. Extinguishing fire.
[Bob] Right engine is out!
[Phoenix] It's still spinning.
Try to restart it.
[Maverick] Phoenix. it's on fire.
don't start...
[Phoenix] Throttling up.
[Maverick] Oh. my God.
- [Bob] We're on fire! We're on fire!
- [Phoenix] Damn it!
- [automated voice] Engine fire. Right.
- [Phoenix] Extinguishing right engine.
[plane engine rumbling]
[Maverick] Phoenix. Bob. punch out!
Punch out!
[Bob] Warning lights everywhere!
Hydraulic failure!
- [operator] Flight controls.
- [Phoenix] I can't control it.
[Bob] We're going down. Phoenix!
We're going in! We're going in!
[Maverick] You can't save it.
Eject! Eject!
- [Phoenix] Eject! Eject! Eject!
- [automated voice] Altitude. Altitude.
[explosion]
They'll keep Phoenix and Bob
in the hospital overnight for observation.
They're gonna be okay.
That's good.
I've never lost a wingman.
You're lucky.
Fly long enough. it'll happen.
There will be others.
Easy for you to say. no wife.
No kids.
Nobody to mourn you when you burn in.
Go home.
Just get some sleep.
[Rooster] Why'd you pull my papers
at the Academy?
Why did you stand in my way?
- You weren't ready.
- Ready for what?
- Huh? Ready to fly like you?
- [Maverick] No. Ready to forget the book.
Trust your instincts.
Don't think. just do.
You think up there. you're dead.
Believe me.
My dad believed in you.
I'm not gonna make the same mistake.
[door opening]
[Warlock] Maverick...
[somber music playing]
[officer] Ready. aim. fire.
- Ready. aim. fire.
- [gunshots]
- [officer] Ready. aim. fire.
[somber music concludes]
[Cyclone] I can only imagine
what you must be feeling right now.
Take some time. whatever you need.
I appreciate that. sir.
but there is no time. The mission...
I'll be taking over the training
from here.
Sir?
We both know
you didn't want this job. Captain.
- Sir. they're not ready.
- Well. it was your job to get them ready.
Sir. they have to believe
that this mission can be flown.
And all you've managed to do
is teach them that it can't.
- Sir...
- [Cyclone] You're grounded. Captain.
Permanently.
- Sir...
- That is all.
I heard.
I'm sorry.
What are you gonna do?
Ice is gone.
What choice do I have?
You'll have to find a way back
on your own.
[Maverick] No. Penny.
I'm out.
This is over.
Pete. if you lost your wingman up there...
you'd keep fighting.
You wouldn't just give up.
Those are your pilots.
If anything happens to them...
you'll never forgive yourself.
I don't know what to do.
[chuckles softly]
But you'll find a way.
I know you will.
[Cyclone] Captain Mitchell
is no longer your instructor.
And as of today.
there are new mission parameters.
- Time to target is now four minutes.
- [beeps]
You'll be entering the valley level
at reduced speed.
Not to exceed 420 knots.
Sir. won't we be giving their planes
time to intercept?
Well. Lieutenant.
you have a fighting chance
against enemy aircraft.
What are the odds of surviving
a head-on collision with a mountain?
You'll be attacking the target
from a higher altitude.
level with the north wall.
Gonna be a little harder
to keep your lase on target.
but you will avoid the High-g climb out.
We'll be sitting ducks for enemy missiles.
[device beeps]
- Who the hell is that?
- [suspenseful music playing]
[Maverick] Maverick to Range Control.
entering Point Alpha.
Confirm green range.
[operator] Uh. Maverick. Range Control.
uh. green range is confirmed.
I don't see an event
scheduled for you. sir.
[Maverick] Well. I'm going anyway.
Nice.
[Maverick] Setting time to target.
two minutes 15 seconds.
Two-fifteen? That's impossible.
[Maverick] Final attack point.
Maverick's inbound.
[plane engine rumbling]
[Maverick grunts]
[beeps]
[grunts]
[Maverick grunts]
[beeps]
[Maverick] Pumping in three. two. one.
[Maverick] Bombs away.
- [beeps]
- [Maverick grunts]
- [Rooster] Bullseye! Holy shit!
- [Coyote groaning]
[Rooster] Yes.
Damn.
[pants]
[suspenseful music concludes]
[Cyclone] You have put me
in a difficult position. Captain.
On the one hand. you have demonstrated
that this mission can be flown.
Perhaps the only way it can be survived.
On the other hand.
you did it by stealing
a multimillion-dollar military aircraft
and flying it in such a manner
that it may never be airworthy again.
Iceman is no longer here to protect you.
I have everything I need
to have you court-martialed
and dishonorably discharged.
So what do I do?
Risk the lives of my pilots
and perhaps the success of this mission?
Or...
risk my career...
by appointing you team leader?
Sir...
I think the admiral's asking
a rhetorical question. Captain.
[soft music playing]
- [bell ringing]
- [crowd cheers]
[waves crashing]
Talk to me. Goose.
[Warlock] Captain Mitchell!
You're where you belong.
Make us proud.
[soft music concludes]
It has been an honor flying with you.
Each one of you
represents the best of the best.
This is a very specific mission.
My choice is a reflection of that
and nothing more.
Choose your two Foxtrot teams.
Payback and Fanboy.
Phoenix and Bob.
[Warlock] And your wingman.
Rooster.
The rest of you will stand by
on the carrier
for any reserve role that's required.
Dismissed.
[intense music playing]
[Warlock] Your target is a clear
and present threat.
A secret uranium enrichment site
under rogue state control.
It's an underground bunker
tucked between these two mountains.
Your route of ingress is heavily defended
by surface-to-air missiles
backed up by fifth-generation fighters.
Once your F-18 strike team
crosses the border.
Tomahawk missiles from the USS Leyte Gulf
will launch a synchronized strike
on the enemy's airfield here.
This will knock out their runway.
But you'll have to contend with
any planes already in the air.
The moment those Tomahawks hit.
the enemy will know you're coming.
Your time to target will be two minutes
and 30 seconds.
Any longer than that.
and you will be exposed to any aircraft
the Tomahawks may have missed.
This is what you've all been training for.
Come home safely.
[plane engine rumbling]
[helicopter whirring]
You give 'em hell!
[man speaking indistinctly over PA]
Sir? Sir!
I...
I just want to say...
[operator] All aboard the aircraft.
get 'em all.
We'll talk...
when we get back.
Hey. Bradley! Bradley!
Hey.
You got this.
[indistinct chatter]
[Hondo] Maverick.
Maverick?
Hey. you with me?
I don't like that look. Mav.
It's the only one I got.
Thank you.
If I don't see you again.
Hondo. thank you.
It's been an honor. Captain.
[Maverick] Dagger One.
up and ready on Catapult One.
[Hangman] Dagger Spare standing by.
Dagger Four. up and ready.
- Dagger Three. up and ready.
- [Rooster] Dagger Two. up and ready.
[comms-crew tech] Support assets airborne.
Strike package ready.
Standing by for launch decision.
Send them.
[plane engine rumbling]
[comms-crew tech] Dagger Two away.
Dagger Three away.
Dagger Four away.
[Maverick] Comanche. Dagger One.
standby check in.
Comanche one-one. set.
Picture clean. recommend Dagger continue.
[Maverick] Copy. Daggers descending
below radar.
- [Fanboy breathes heavily]
- [Payback breathes heavily]
[Rooster breathes heavily]
[device beeping]
[comms-crew tech] Daggers now below radar.
Switching to E-2 picture.
[Maverick] Here we go.
Enemy territory up ahead.
Feet dry in 60 seconds.
Comanche. Dagger One. Picture.
Comanche. Picture clean.
Decision is yours.
[Maverick] Copy.
[Rooster breathing heavily]
Dagger attack.
[explosion]
[comms-crew tech 2] Tomahawks airborne.
No turning back now.
[Maverick] Daggers.
assume attack formation.
Daggers set. Proceeding to target.
Two minutes and 30 seconds
in three. two. one. mark.
[beeps]
- [Rooster] Two mark.
- [Phoenix] Three mark.
[Payback] Four mark.
[clock ticking]
[Maverick exhales] Going in.
First SAM site overhead.
[Phoenix] Looks like we're clear
on radar. Mav.
[Maverick] Let's not take it for granted.
[Rooster pants] More SAMs!
Three o'clock high!
[Bob] We got two minutes to target.
[Fanboy] Copy. We're two seconds
behind. Rooster. We got to move.
[comms-crew tech 2] Thirty seconds
to Tomahawk impact on enemy airstrip.
- [beeps]
- [comms-crew tech] Dagger. Comanche.
We're picking up two bandits.
Single group. two contacts.
- Where the hell they come from?
- Long-range patrol?
[Phoenix] Comanche. what's their heading?
[comms-crew tech] Bullseye 09. 050.
tacked southwest.
[Rooster] They're headed away from us.
They don't know we're here.
[Maverick] The second those Tomahawks
hit the air base.
those bandits are gonna move
to defend the target.
We have to get there
before they do. increase speed.
[Phoenix] We got you. Mav.
Don't wait for me.
[Rooster breathing heavily]
[comms-crew tech] Sir. Daggers Two
and Four are behind schedule.
Time to target. one minute 20.
[comms-crew tech 2] Tomahawk impact
in three. two...
[explosions]
[comms-crew tech 2] Impact.
enemy runway is destroyed.
They know we're coming now.
[comms-crew tech] Bandits are switching
course to defend the target.
[Maverick] Rooster. where are you?
[Fanboy] Come on. Rooster.
Bandits inbound.
We got to make up time now.
Let's turn and burn.
[Maverick panting]
Heads up. Phoenix.
[Bob] Whoa!
[comms-crew tech] Sir.
bandits are two minutes from target.
Daggers are one minute from target.
Come on. Rooster. Move it or lose it.
[Fanboy] Guys. we're falling behind.
We really gotta move.
If we don't increase our speed. right now.
those bandits are gonna be waiting for us
when we reach the target.
[Rooster] Talk to me. Dad.
[Maverick] Come on. kid. you can do it.
Don't think. just do.
[Rooster breathes deeply. grunts]
[Payback] Jesus. Rooster. not that fast!
- [Maverick] That's it. kid. that's it.
- [Rooster] All right. let's go.
[Fanboy] Damn. Rooster. take it easy.
[comms-crew tech] Sir. Dagger Two
is reengaging.
All right. now hit your target
and come home.
[Maverick] Thirty seconds to target.
Bob. check your laser.
[Bob] Air-to-ground check complete.
Laser code verified. 1688.
Laser is a go!
[Rooster] Watch your heads. [pants]
[Fanboy] Oh. shit! Shit!
- [Rooster] Payback. you with me?
- [Payback] Right behind you.
[Maverick] Phoenix.
stand by for pop-up strike.
[Phoenix] Dagger Three in position.
[Maverick] Popping in three. two. one.
[breathing heavily]
[Phoenix breathes heavily]
[Maverick grunts]
[Maverick] Get me eyes
on that target. Bob.
[Bob] Dagger Three.
- Stand by. Mav.
- [Maverick] Come on. Bob. come on.
[Bob] Stand by.
- I've got it. Captured!
- [Maverick] Target acquired. Bombs away.
[grunts]
[Phoenix grunts]
[Maverick grunts]
[Bob pants]
[explosion]
[Bob] We've got impact!
Check. direct hit! Direct hit!
That's miracle number one.
[Maverick] Dagger Two. status.
[Rooster] Almost there. Mav. Almost there.
Fanboy. where's my laser?
[Fanboy] Rooster. there's something wrong
with this laser!
Shit! Deadeye! Deadeye! Deadeye!
[Maverick] Come on. guys.
we're running out of time. Get it online!
- [Fanboy] I'm trying! I'm trying!
- [Maverick] Come on. Fanboy!
[Fanboy] Nearly there! Nearly there!
- [Phoenix breathes heavily]
- [Maverick grunts]
[Payback] Come on. Fanboy. get it online.
[Rooster] There's no time.
I'm dropping blind.
- [Fanboy] Rooster. I got this! I got this!
- [Rooster] No time. Pull up.
- [Payback] Rooster. wait!
- [Rooster] Bombs away! Bombs away!
[pants. groans]
[explosions]
- [Phoenix] Bullseye! Bullseye! Bullseye!
- [crowd cheers]
Miracle number two.
Now they're in Coffin Corner.
[Maverick] We're not out of this yet.
- Here it comes.
- [radar buzzing]
[Maverick] Radar warning!
Smoke in the air. Phoenix. break right.
[Phoenix] Emergency jettison.
Dagger Three defending.
- [Bob] Here comes another one!
- [Maverick] Dagger One defending.
[explosions]
[Maverick] Rooster. status.
[Rooster grunts]
[Rooster] Oh. my God.
Smoke in the air! Smoke in the air!
[Fanboy] Break right. Payback!
Break right!
- [Payback] Breaking right.
- [Fanboy] Oh. my God! Here they come!
[Payback] SAM on your six. Rooster!
[Rooster] Deploying countermeasures.
- [explosion]
- [Rooster] Negative contact.
[Maverick] Dagger One defending.
- [Phoenix] Talk to me. Bob.
- [Bob] Break right. Phoenix! Break right!
Mav. nine o'clock! Nine o'clock!
[Payback] Rooster. two more on your six.
[Rooster] Dagger Two. defending.
- [explosion]
- [Rooster grunts]
- [Maverick] Payback. SAM on your nose.
- [Payback] Dagger Four defending.
- [Bob] Rooster. tally. seven o'clock!
- [Phoenix] Talk to me. Bob!
- [Bob] On our six!
- [Rooster] Dagger Two defending.
- [Maverick] Phoenix. break right!
- [Phoenix] I see it! I see it!
[indistinct chatter]
[Rooster grunts] Dagger Two defending.
Shit. I'm out of flares!
[Maverick] Rooster. evade. evade!
[Rooster] I can't shake 'em!
They're on me! They're on me!
[explosion]
- [Rooster] Mav!
- [explosion]
[Rooster] Mav! No!
[Phoenix] Dagger One is hit!
I repeat. Dagger One is hit!
Maverick is down.
[Rooster] Dagger One. status! Status!
Anyone see him? Does anyone see him?
- Dagger One. come in!
- [Payback] I didn't see a parachute.
We have to circle back.
[comms-crew tech] Comanche.
Bandits inbound. Single group. hot.
Recommend Dagger flow south.
One minute to intercept.
- Get 'em back to the carrier now.
- All Daggers flow to ECP.
- You have bandits headed for you.
- [Rooster] What about Maverick?
Tell him there's nothing he can do
for Maverick. not in a goddamn F-18.
Dagger Spare request permission
to launch and fly air cover.
Negative. Spare.
- Launch search and rescue.
- Negative. Not with bandits in the air.
- But. sir. Maverick is still out there.
- We are not losing anyone else today.
Get 'em home now.
- [keyboard keys clacking]
- Dagger. you are not to engage.
Repeat. do not engage.
[comms-crew tech] Dagger Two.
return to carrier. Acknowledge.
Acknowledge.
[Phoenix] Rooster.
those bandits are closing.
We can't go back.
[Bob] Rooster. he's gone.
- Maverick's gone.
- [Rooster pants]
[intense music concludes]
[Maverick breathes heavily]
[gasps]
- [wind whooshing]
- [birds chirping]
- [helicopter whirring]
- [intense music playing]
[explosion]
No. no.
[device beeping]
[explosion]
[comms-crew tech 2] Dagger Two is hit.
Dagger Two is hit.
[comms-crew tech] Dagger Two. come in.
Dagger Two. do you copy?
Dagger Two. come in.
- [pants]
- [intense music concludes]
You all right?
- Yeah. I'm good. you all right?
- [Maverick] Jesus.
Okay.
- What the hell?
- What are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
You think I took that missile
so you could be down here with me?
You should be back on the carrier by now!
I saved your life!
I saved your life. that's the whole point.
- What the hell were you even thinking?
- You told me not to think!
[both pant]
Well... [pants]
...it's good to see you.
[sniffs. pants] It's good to see you too.
- So. what's the plan? [pants]
- [pants]
[horn blaring]
[intense music playing]
You're not serious.
[indistinct chatter]
[Rooster] You've got to be shitting me.
An F-14?
I shot down three MiGs in one of those.
We don't even know
if that bag of ass can fly.
- Let's find out.
- Mav!
Okay.
- [horn blaring]
- [indistinct chatter]
- [Rooster] There's guys up there. Mav.
- Yeah.
- [Rooster] There's more over there.
- [Maverick] Okay.
- [Rooster] Let's start running.
- [Maverick] Yeah. run. run.
Once... Once I give you the signal
for air.
you're gonna flip this switch
until the needle gets to 120.
When the engine starts.
you got to pull out the pins
and disconnect everything.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
[machine whirring]
Yes!
Once I'm up. stow the ladder.
Okay. wow.
It's been a minute. huh. Mav?
- [device beeping]
- [plane engine buzzing]
[plane engine rumbling]
[device beeping]
Oh. my God. this thing is so old.
All right.
- Canopy?
- Clear.
Both runways are cratered.
How we gonna get
this museum piece in the air?
Why are the wings coming out. Mav?
[plane engine rumbling]
Mav. this is a taxiway. not a runway.
This is a very short taxiway. Mav.
You just hang on.
Holy shit!
Come on. Needle's alive. Come on.
- Mav?
- [Maverick] That's it. come on! Come on!
All right.
- Mav!
- [Maverick] Here we go.
[Rooster] Holy shit.
Sir. we're receiving a signal
from Rooster's ESAT.
But there seems to be a malfunction.
- Have you lost him?
- No. sir. He's supersonic.
He's airborne.
In what?
Sir. Overwatch reports
an F-14 Tomcat is airborne
and on course for our position.
Can't be. It... It can't be!
Maverick.
Okay. Rooster.
get us in touch with the boat.
I'm working on it.
Radio's out. no radar.
Everything's dead back here.
- What do I do? Talk me through it.
- [Maverick] Okay. first the radio.
Throw the. uh...
the UHF-2 circuit breaker. Try that.
There's 300 breakers back here.
Anything more specific?
I don't know.
That was your dad's department.
I'll figure it out.
[plane engine rumbling]
Mav. tally two. five o'clock. low.
What do we do?
Okay. listen. Just be cool.
If they knew who we were.
we'd be dead already.
Well. here they come.
- What's your plan?
- Just put your mask on.
Remember. we're on the same team.
Just wave and smile.
[Rooster] What's that signal?
What's he saying?
[Maverick] Yeah. no idea.
I have no idea what he's saying.
[Rooster] What about that one? Any idea?
[Maverick] No. never seen that one either.
Oh. shit. His wingman is moving
into weapons envelope.
All right. listen up.
When I tell you.
you grab those rings above your head.
That's the ejection handle.
[Rooster] Mav. can we outrun these guys?
[Maverick] Not their missiles and guns.
[Rooster] Then it's a dogfight.
[Maverick] An F-14
against fifth-gen fighters?
[Rooster] It's not the plane.
it's the pilot.
You'd go after 'em if I wasn't here.
[Maverick] But you are here.
[Rooster] Come on. Mav.
Don't think.
Just do.
[Maverick breathes heavily]
[grunts]
[Maverick] Tell me when you see smoke
in the air.
[device beeping]
[Rooster] Smoke in the air!
Smoke in the air!
[Maverick] Hang on.
[explosion]
[Rooster] Yeah. Mav!
Splash one! Splash one!
[device beeping]
- [Rooster] Here comes another one.
- [Maverick grunts]
[Maverick] Rooster. flares! Now. now. now!
[explosion]
[Maverick] Splitting the throttles.
- Coming around.
- [Rooster grunts]
[Maverick] Give me tone. Give me tone.
- [Rooster] You got him. Mav! You got him!
- [Maverick] Taking the shot.
What the...
[Rooster] Holy shit!
What the fuck was that?
[Maverick] Hang on. We gotta get low.
The terrain will confuse
his targeting system.
[Rooster] Here he comes!
[beeps]
[Maverick grunts]
[Maverick] Talk to me. Rooster.
Where is he?
[Rooster] He's still on us!
- We took a hit! We took a hit!
- [Maverick] Oh. damn it!
[Rooster] Come on. Mav.
do some of that pilot shit.
[Maverick] Brace yourself. [grunts]
- [Rooster] Holy shit.
- [Maverick grunts]
[Maverick] I got tone. Taking the shot.
Damn it! [grunts]
Out of missiles. Switching to guns.
Come on. Mav. come on.
- [Rooster] You got him. Mav!
- [Maverick] It's not over yet.
- One last chance.
- [Rooster] You can do this.
[Maverick] Come on. Maverick.
[device beeping]
[explosion]
[Rooster] Yes! Splash two!
[Maverick pants]
[device beeps]
- [Rooster] Mav. I got the radio on.
- [Maverick] Outstanding.
- Get us in touch with the boat.
- [Rooster] Copy that.
[device beeping]
[Maverick] Oh. my God.
[Rooster grunts]
Where the hell is this guy?
He's on our nose.
Damn it. we're out of ammo.
Smoke in the air! Rooster. flares!
[Rooster] That was close.
We're out of flares. Mav.
Shit. he's already on us.
[grunts] This is not good.
[Maverick grunts]
- [Rooster] We took another hit!
- [Maverick] No! No! No! No!
[Rooster groans] We can't take much more
of this.
[Maverick] We can't outrun this guy.
we got to eject.
- [Rooster] What?
- [Maverick] We need altitude.
Pull the ejection handles
the second I tell you.
- [Rooster] Mav. wait!
- [Maverick] Rooster. there's no other way.
Eject! Eject! Eject!
Rooster. pull the handle! Eject!
[Rooster] It's not working!
[device beeping]
[Rooster] Mav! [pants]
[Maverick] I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Goose.
[device beeping]
[explosion]
[Hangman] Good afternoon.
ladies and gentlemen.
This is your savior speaking.
- Please fasten your seat belts...
- [Maverick sighs]
[Hangman] ...return your tray tables
to their locked and upright positions...
- [Rooster laughs]
- [Hangman] ...and prepare for landing.
[Rooster] Hey. Hangman. you look good.
[Hangman] I am good. Rooster.
I'm very good.
I'll see you back on deck.
[Maverick breathes heavily]
[Maverick] Maverick is downwind.
no front landing gear.
No tail hook.
Pull the cable and raise the barricade.
- [man] Foul deck! Foul deck!
- Raise the barricade!
[Hondo] Go!
[Rooster] Please don't tell me
we lost an engine.
[Maverick] All right.
I won't tell you that.
[Rooster] Okay.
[Maverick pants]
- [Maverick] You good?
- [Rooster] Yeah. I'm good.
[Maverick sighs]
[crowd cheers. applauds]
- Chalked yourself another kill.
- That makes two.
Mav has five. makes him an ace.
Captain Mitchell! Captain Mitchell!
Sir!
Thank you for saving my life.
It's what my dad would've done.
[intense music concludes]
[dramatic music playing]
[door opening]
Hey. Mav.
Jimmy.
Is...
Is Penny around?
Uh. she took Amelia on a sailing trip.
Did she say when she'd be back?
[Jimmy] You know. she didn't.
Can I get you anything?
Right in there.
[dramatic music concludes]
["Hold My Hand" by Lady Gaga playing]
♪ Hold my hand
Everything will be okay ♪
♪ I heard from the heavens
That clouds have been gray ♪
♪ Pull me close ♪
♪ Wrap me in your aching arms ♪
♪ I see that you're hurtin'
Why'd you take so long ♪
♪ To tell me you need me? ♪
♪ I see that you're bleeding
You don't need to show me again ♪
♪ But if you decide to
I'll ride in this life with you ♪
♪ I won't let go till the end ♪
♪ So cry tonight ♪
♪ But don't you let go of my hand ♪
♪ You can cry every last tear ♪
♪ I won't leave till I understand ♪
♪ Promise me just hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand. hold my
Hold my hand. my hand ♪
♪ I'll be right here. hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand. hold my
Hold my hand. my hand ♪
♪ I'll be right here. hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand ♪
♪ My hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand. hold my hand
Hold my hand. hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand ♪
♪ I heard from the heavens ♪
["Hold My Hand" by Lady Gaga concludes]
[classical music playing]
[classical music concludes]
[soft music playing]
[soft music concludes]
[instrumental music playing]
[instrumental music concludes]
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-